You sure have a good appetite. It's a good thing.
你胃口真好 这是件好事
Grow big and strong, Rokurota.
要长得高高壮壮的 陆郎太
Snack time is over? Is it play time already?
吃完点心了？ 已经是游戏时间了吗？
Play.
玩
Get back, Sagiri!
快回来 佐切！
Lord Genji!
源嗣大人！
You need medical attention.
你需要立刻治疗
Run… Sagiri…
快跑 佐切
I'm not going to make it.
我不行了
Hurry… run…
快 跑啊
Gabimaru.
画眉丸
Is he one of the sinners, or is he a monster?
他是罪人之一还是怪物？
I don't see any damage on him.
他一点伤都没有
That is… The Giant of Bizen, Rokurota.
那是备前的大巨人 陆郎太
The beheader in charge of him is…
负责他的斩首者是…
Lord Eizen.
埃森大人
His eyes are like an animal preying on its catch.
他的眼睛就像在捕食猎物的动物
Escaping as a group is nearly impossible.
集体逃脱几乎是不可能的
I have no choice…
没办法了 我只能
but to kill it.
杀了他
But how should I do this?
但我该怎么做呢？
My kick was practically useless.
踢他基本上是没用的
His strength rivals that of the shinobi of Iwagakure.
他的力量堪比石隐村的忍者
The Law of the Shinobi, rule number nine.
《忍者法则》第九条
Analyze your enemy's capabilities.
分析敌人的能力
I need to know its strength first.
我得先知道他的实力
Get back or you'll die!
快回来 否则你会死的！
But…
但是…
It has more strength than me.
他比我更有力量
How long are you going to stand there and watch?
你还要站在那里看多久？
Help me and show me your ninja skills.
快来帮我 让我看看你的忍术
Fight together as promised.
像你承诺过的那样战斗
Yeah, yeah. I'll keep my promise.
是啊 我会遵守承诺的
Remember, you give us strength. And I give you intel.
别忘了 你给我们力量 我给你情报
Go Gabimaru! You can do it, Gabimaru!
加油 画眉丸 你可以的 画眉丸
Go, go! You can do it! You're almighty.
加油 你可以的 你是万能的
Gabimaru! Good luck!
画眉丸 加油喔
What an immense swing.
多么巨大的挥拳
Maybe if I focus on destroying its fist…
也许如果我专注于摧毁他的拳头…
His detection and response are fast.
他的反应速度太快了
Above all, it's intuitive.
更重要的是 他的反应是靠直觉
That hand is indefensible. If it touches me, I'm dead.
那只手是防备不住的 如果他碰到我 我就死定了
If that's the case… Ninja Art, Thunder Stones.
如果是这样的话…忍术 雷石
This type of attack doesn't work on him.
这种攻击在他身上不起作用
Ninja Art, Flexible Blade.
忍术 灵活刀片
It's as strong as a steel sword, but it's useless too.
它和钢剑一样坚固 但这也没用
NINJA ART FLEXIBLE BLADE
（忍术 灵活刀片）
Is there anything else?
还有别的什么吗？
I have to think of an attack that I can use from a distance.
我得想出一种可以从远处使用的攻击
Enough already. Don't waste your time.
够了 别浪费你的时间了
Hurry… get out of here, Sagiri.
快点 离开这里 佐切
Don't give up, Sir!
大人 不要放弃
I can save you as long as I stop the bleeding.
只要能止住血 我就能救你
You're strange.
你真奇怪
Before, you were daring like a man.
之前 你像个男人一样大胆
But now I feel the compassion of a woman.
但现在我感受到了一个女人的同情心
This is not a matter of man or woman.
这跟男女无关
I just don't want you to die!
我只是不想你死
Is that your way of life?
那是你的生活方式吗？
Whether man or woman, whether strong or weak,
无论男人还是女人 无论强弱
you accept opposites as they are, not dividing them.
你接受他们的对立面 而不是分裂他们
The Middle Way. That is what you truly believe in.
中庸之道 那才是你真正相信的
I finally understand.
我终于明白了
The sword is the heart of a samurai.
剑是武士的心脏
I entrust this to you.
我把这个委托给你
Rokurota likely killed Eizen.
陆郎太很可能杀了埃森
If you are a true samurai,
如果你是个真正的武士
I won't tell you to run anymore.
我不会再叫你逃跑了
Kill Rokurota.
杀了陆郎太
Please, Yamada Asaemon Sagiri.
拜托了 山田浅右卫门佐切
Close combat is dangerous and weapons are useless.
近战是危险的 武器都没有用
If only I could use a fire technique.
要是我能用火术就好了
If there are two of us, maybe I could create a blind spot.
如果我们有两个人 也许我可以制造一个盲点
If I put the blade into the stretched muscles,
如果我把刀刺入伸展的肌肉
I can cut even the most well-trained body.
即使是训练有素的身体我也能切开
No matter how abnormal you may be.
不管你多么不正常
It's the same as beheading.
这跟斩首一样
You need to know the body's skeletal structure and weave through the gaps.
你需要了解身体的骨骼结构 并穿过缝隙
This is… the sword of Yamada Asaemon.
这是山田浅右卫门的剑
Gabimaru.
画眉丸
You're just in time. I needed a helping hand.
你来得正是时候 我需要帮助
-Please give me a hand.
-请帮助我
Um… I'd like to go and tend to the others.
那个…我想去照顾其他人
Huh? But it's too late now.
什么？但现在已经太晚了
Plus, you're not in the position to do that, right?
还有 这不该由你来做吧？
All this racket they're causing and I don't see one monster in sight.
他们引起这么大的动静 我也没看到任何怪物
Don't you think this observation is more useful?
你不觉得在这里观察更有用吗？
If they die, I'll just make a run for it.
如果他们死了 我就会逃跑
His bleeding has already stopped.
他的血已经止住了
That wasn't enough to inflict damage.
这不足以造成伤害
We need to kill him with one blow.
我们需要一击杀死他
The only way is to aim for the neck.
唯一的方法是瞄准他的颈部
But I can't reach his neck. It's too high.
但我够不到他的颈部 太高了
So we'll split into two.
所以我们要分开行动
You go for the leg and bring him down on his knees.
你去攻击他的腿 让他跪下
-You make it sound so easy. -Huh?
-你说起来容易 -什么？
You can do it, right?
你能做到的吧？
I'll distract him.
我来分散他注意力
What the--!
搞什么…
-Are you okay? -Yes.
-你没事吧？ -没事
He's the execution target and the one who hurt Genji.
他是处决对象 也是那个伤害源嗣的人
If I'm too eager, I'll lose my grip on the sword.
如果我太着急 会失去对剑的控制
Be calmer. Be rational, not compassionate.
冷静点 要理性 不要有同情心
He's coming. Cut him again!
他来了 再砍他一次！
My foot… Did I mess it up when I tried to dodge the last attack?
我的脚…我是不是 在躲避最后一击的时候搞砸了？
Fending it off unscathed requires great skill.
毫发无损地抵挡他需要高超的技巧
A mere slap can be like a cannon.
被他扇一下就如同被大炮轰
I have to stay calm. One hit and I'm done for.
我必须保持冷静 被击中一下我就完了
It's impossible to cut him unless he's still.
砍到他是不可能的 除非他静止不动
When he moves, the gap between the bones closes.
当他移动时 骨头之间的间隙闭合 我无法把刀片放进去
In a beheading, we cut the neck with the head hanging down.
在斩首时 我们将头垂下再砍脖子
To finish it with a single blow, we need the neck in a crouched position.
如果要一击毙命 我们需要使脖子处于蜷曲状态
But if the blade cannot even pass through the limbs,
但如果刀片都无法穿过四肢
getting him in that position is almost impossible.
让他处于那个状态几乎不可能
I'd say we're in a pickle.
我想我们陷入困境了
Is that sound… coming from his stomach?
那个声音是从他肚子里发出来的？
What the heck is this?!
那是什么啊？
What a loud sound.
好大的声音
Gabimaru!
画眉丸！
I knew we were dealing with a giant with brute strength but…
我知道我们在对付一个 有蛮力的巨人 但是…
I think I can endure this.
我想我能忍受这个
By the skin of my teeth.
勉强过关
No!
不！
This is bad. I have to get back on my feet.
这样不行 我必须重新站起来
This isn't fatal. I have to get up!
这不是致命的 我得站起来！
Its over…
结束了
Stay calm. I need to deal with this in a calm manner.
保持冷静 我需要冷静地处理这件事
Keep your emotions under control. Be rational.
控制好你的情绪 理性一点
Stay calm. Let go of any rage.
保持冷静 不要愤怒
Create a calm mind.
营造平静的心态
The Middle Way. That is what you truly believe in.
中庸之道 那才是你真正相信的
Don't divide them.
不要分裂它们
Accept… opposites as they are.
接受对立面
Both in feeling and reason.
无论是在感觉上还是在理性上
Let your emotions be your strength. Never lose sight of your reason.
让你的情绪成为你的力量 永远不要忘记你的理由
Neither be still nor furious.
既不要静止 也不要愤怒
Choose the middle way!
选择中庸之道
She's amazing.
她好棒
She's 12 in rank in swordsmanship but…
她的剑术排名第12 但是
the rank of the Yamada family is not determined by pure skill alone.
山田家的等级不是单纯靠技能决定的
It is based on the suitability of the next head of the family clan.
它是根据下一任族长的适合度而定
If you are a woman, you will be treated unfairly.
如果你是女人 你会受到不公平的对待
If it is based solely on skill, she is…
如果单凭实力 她就是第一
As a soldier on the battlefield, Sagiri lacks experience.
作为战场上的士兵 佐切缺乏经验
But… when her purpose and heart are aligned,
但是 当她的目标和内心一致时
and when all her hesitation disappears,
当她所有的犹豫都消失时
her swordsmanship is more than first rate.
她的剑术不止一流
She may shrink away from the monsters on the island,
她也许会因为岛上的怪物而退缩
but as an Asaemon,
但作为山田家的人
she doesn't even flinch when dealing with sinners.
她在与罪人打交道时从不退缩
She's a stubborn one.
她是个固执的人
I was right.
我是对的
I knew from the time I first met her,
从见到她的第一次我就知道
this woman… is strong.
这个女人很强
Aim…
瞄准
for the crouched neck.
弯下的脖子
This isn't going to be easy.
这可不简单
Can we somehow keep its head down?
我们能想办法让他低着头吗？
It might be a bit risky,
可能会有点冒险
but I have a plan.
但我有个计划
The Giant of Bizen. Getting up close to him is suicide.
备前的大巨人 靠近他就是自杀
Weapons are useless.
武器都是无用的
The only way is to use a sword to cut through the tissue, then cut off the head.
唯一的办法就是用剑切开组织 然后砍下脑袋
Not only is superior physical ability required, but
这不仅需要超强的体能
we need the skills of a true beheader, the skills of a Yamada Asaemon.
更需要来自真正的 山田浅右卫门的斩首技术
But with that massive body and swiftness, how can we get the blade in him?
但以那庞大、敏捷的身躯 我们怎样才能把刀片刺入他体内？
If that's the case…
如果是这样的话…
Oh, shit!
糟了
We have to get out of here, Senta.
我们得离开这里 仙汰
Ninja Art: Thunder Stones, Fire Monk Version.
忍术 雷石 火僧版
Ninja Art, Wind Sewing, Fire Monk Version.
忍术 风缝 火僧版
Ninja Art, Giant Stone, Fire Monk Version.
忍术 巨石 火僧版
Ninja Art, Thorn Quilt, Fire Monk Version.
忍术 荆棘被 火僧版
You can't go on any longer.
你不能再继续了
You've already done enough.
你做的已经够多了
How far are we going to go?
我们还要跑多远？
As far as we can, you four-eyed raccoon dog.
越远越好 你这个四眼貉
Their target isn't Rokurota.
他们的目标不是陆郎太
They plan to burn the entire area.
他们打算烧毁整个区域
-No way. -They're gonna use the smoke.
-不可能 -他们要用烟雾
A lot of smoke will burn from the oil in the trees.
大量的烟雾会点燃树上的油
Once the trees and leaves start burning, smoke will quickly build up.
一旦树木和树叶开始燃烧 烟雾会很快积聚
The nature of the smoke is that it moves towards the top.
烟雾的性质是向顶部移动
If he cries and moves around, he'll be short of breath,
如果他哭喊着四处走 他会呼吸急促
and breathe in a ton of smoke.
从而吸入大量的烟
The only thing more harmful than fire or heat is the poison
唯一比火或热更有害的 是烟雾中的有毒物质
in the smoke which causes fainting if inhaled.
如果吸入 会导致昏厥
Poison?
有毒物质？
That is, carbon monoxide.
也就是一氧化碳
It combines with the hemoglobin in the blood,
它会与血液中的血红蛋白结合
and causes rapid depletion of oxygen throughout the body.
并迅速耗尽全身氧气
Also known as carbon monoxide poisoning.
也称为一氧化碳中毒
That was intense, but as long as you stay low, you won't breath in smoke.
那很厉害 但只要你保持低位 就不会吸入烟雾
We're safe down here.
我们在这里很安全
I feel like I'll burn to death.
我觉得我会被烧死
Will we go down first?
我们会先倒下吗？
Or will it come down to us?
还是他会倒在我们身上？
Cut him now! Do it before he gets back up!
现在砍他！在他爬起来之前！
Stay calm,
保持冷静
yet be fierce.
但要凶猛
I'm hungry. I wanna play.
我饿了 我想玩
I wanna play! I wanna play!
我要玩
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Why don't I get full?
为什么我吃不饱？
Why won't anyone play with me?
为什么没人跟我一起玩？
Sorry for getting you worked up.
抱歉 让你生气了
I scared you, didn't I?
我吓到你了 是不是？
I'm sorry. It's because I'm inexperienced.
对不起 是因为我没有经验
But you don't need to worry anymore.
但你不用再担心了
No one hates you.
没有人恨你
There's no one who hates you now.
现在没有人恨你了
The perished soul…
逝去的灵魂
May you rest quietly in peace.
愿你安息
The flames are getting stronger.
火势越来越大了
The monsters may come for us. Let's get out of here.
怪物可能会来找我们 我们离开这里吧
Lord Genji.
源嗣大人
Hey! Hurry up or you'll burn to death.
喂！快点 不然你会被烧死的
Never mind sinners,
别说罪人了
we can't even mourn our comrades.
我们连同僚都无法为其哀悼
We must keep our hearts strong, and stay strong.
我们要保持强大的内心 保持坚强
Stay strong…
保持坚强
Whether strong or weak,
无论强弱
you accept opposites as they are, not dividing them.
你都接受他们的对立面 而不是分裂它们
That is what you truly believe in.
那才是你真正相信的
They came after us after all.
他们还是来追我们了
They're going in the direction of the flames.
他们正朝着火焰的方向去
Normally it's an animal's natural instinct to avoid fire.
通常来说 避开火焰是动物的本能
Now we know for sure that they aren't natural life forms.
现在我们能确定 它们不是自然的生命形式
I have no choice.
我别无选择
Let's go to where the monsters are.
我们去怪物所在的地方吧
Isn't it dangerous?
那不危险吗？
I guess… but we have no choice.
我想是吧 但我们没有选择
For now, the monsters are our only clue to the elixir.
目前来说 怪物是我们 找到长生不老药的唯一线索
I'm still hurt from earlier.
我还受着伤
I want to rest. This is all a pain in the ass.
我想休息 这一切都让人头疼
-Do you want to turn back then? -No!
-那你要回头吗？ -不！
If it's a clue, no matter how small or dangerous, I won't give up.
如果这是一个线索 无论多小、多危险 我都不会放弃
I will find the elixir
我会找到长生不老药
and I'll see my wife as soon as possible.
我会尽快见到我的妻子
And you? Aren't you worried about the safety of your comrades?
你呢？你不担心你战友的安危吗？
Everyone here,
这里的每一个人
is risking their lives to fulfill their role.
都冒着生命危险履行他们的职责
Excessive concern would be disrespectful.
过分关心是不尊重
If we truly care for our comrades, we need to find the elixir
如果我们真正关心我们的战友 我们需要找到长生不老药
and relieve them of this role.
结束他们的任务
We're finally on the same page.
我们终于达成共识了
Don't forget that I'm still watching over you.
别忘了 我依然在看着你
It's them.
是他们
It's the fox and raccoon dog. They ran this far?
是狐狸和貉 他们跑了这么远？
Hey! Guys! What happened to working as a team?
喂 伙计们 说好的团队合作呢？
Is this…
这是…
Is this a village?
这是个村庄吗？
What else does it look like?
还会是什么呢？
If this place is indeed Shinsenkyo,
如果这里的确是神仙境
is this the village where the sages live?
那么这就是圣人居住的村庄吗？
This tastes awful! It doesn't fill my stomach, even a little.
这味道糟透了 它不能填饱我的肚子 哪怕是一点点
Is it safe to eat that?
吃那个安全吗？
I'm not eating it, I'm drinking it.
我不是在吃 我是在喝
The blood of animals makes up the mountains, right?
动物的血组成了山脉 对吧？
About what you said earlier,
关于你刚才说的
what about the sages?
圣人怎么了？
They are fictitious people.
他们是虚构的人
A kind of superhuman in Chinese philosophy.
是中国哲学中的一种超人类
They usually appear as an old man, and manipulate mysterious arts.
他们通常以老人的形象出现 并操纵神秘的幻术
They are said to be immortal.
据说 他们是永生的
And they may be on this island.
他们也许就在岛上
Essentially, the inhabitants of this Paradise are sages,
本质上 这个天堂里的居民是圣人
not monsters.
而不是怪物
Bull shit.
胡说八道
Let's just kill those old men then.
我们还是把那些老人杀了吧
Maybe this time, they'll satisfy my appetite.
也许这一次他们会满足我的胃口
You're joking, right?
你开玩笑的吧？
Brother?
哥哥？
I sense something.
我感觉到了什么东西
The next one better be tasty.
下一个会更美味
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻译：朱未耒